Manuel J. Molina



ADDRESS Sausalito, CA 94965 USA



PHONE 650-823-7629



LINKEDIN https://www.linked in.com/in/manuel-j -molina/



GITHUB https://janmanjan. github.io/

EDUCATION

BA/Psychology, Minor in Economics

Loyola Marymount University, Los Angeles, CA

2012-2014, 2016-2018

SUMMARY

Data Science fellow with a few years of experience in behavioral psychology. My background enables me to flexibly tackle problems in an ever-changing environment. With my unique perspective, I look to optimize impact using statistical analysis.

SKILLS

Data Science: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Natural Language Processing, Web Scraping, Time Series Analysis, Image Processing

Programming: Python, HTML, SQL, PySpark, Git

Visualization: Matplotlib, Seaborn, Tableau, Scikit Learn, Tensorflow, Keras, Pandas, Numpy

Additional Skills: Client Relations, Cross Cultural Relations

EXPERIENCE

Data Science Fellow • General Assembly • Remote [November 2021 - March 2022]

- Completed 500 hours, 5 projects, and 20+ labs in an immersive course with python programming in Jupyter Labs. The course covered visualization tools, statistical methods, and machine learning algorithms for regression & classification problems.
- Trained a convolutional neural network on MRI scans to classify between schizophrenic and non-schizophrenic brains.
- Built clustering models and a web application to investigate the relationship between climate change and air pollution related mortality rates.
- Utilized natural language processing to create several models that classified thousands of scraped Reddit posts.

Registered Behavior Tech 2 • Autism Learning Partners • San Francisco, CA [September 2019 - January 2022]

- Applied evidence-based behavior intervention techniques utilizing an online data tracking system with 7 children diagnosed with Autism, from 4-13 years old, under the supervision of a Board Certified Behavior Analyst.
- Improved life-skills via interventions that are designed to increase desired behavior in social contexts, and decrease maladaptive behaviors

Team Leader • AIESEC AdMU • Quezon City, Philippines [August 2014 - March 2016]

• Developed, managed, and pitched a microfinance project in a team of 4. Leveraged 50 financially literate international undergraduate and graduate students as consultants for 25 local micro-entrepreneurs. Utilized 4 local micro-lending institutions and 2 non-government organizations.